Thank you, o great god Fukumoto! - by Me
Kaiji returns to the silver screen!
And we give you loyal anime watchers a sneak peek!
Tonight, for the final ep, we bring you a making-of!
Behind-the-scenes footage of Kaiji taking down the Bog!
I swallowed the Bog!
You have to see the Bog go down in Kaiji 2!
And now, a quiz.
Great God Fukumoto's Present Quiz!
Kiyomi is whose daughter?
A: Koji Ishida.
B: Jun'ichi Ishida.
C: Riko Higashio.
Well? Whose!?
The reward is a shikishi signed by the Great God Fukumoto himself!
Visit our mobile site to enter!
The anime may be over, but Kaiji is just getting started!
The Future is In Our Hands
It's paying out!
出る！出る！
湯水のように！
The balls are flowing like water!
幸せー！
I'm so happy!
確保の命令です　会長から
We have direct orders from the Chairman to secure you.
お立ちください
Stand up.
さあ
うっ…
Now.
おっちゃん ちょっと頼む
えっ？
Pops, keep an eye on this for a minute.
Uh, sure, I guess.
そ… それはええが…
一条
Ichijou!
戻ってこい
Come back!
できる！お前ならできる！
You can do it. I know you can do it.
どこへ行こうと
必ずその場を支配できる
No matter where you end up, you'll claw your way to the top of the heap.
策略 知略に長けた
悪党だろ お前は！
You're a sly, scheming scumbag.
So claw your way back up!
這い上がってこい！
ザコを蹴散らし 追い払い
Wipe out the small-time losers down there...
這い上がってこい！
倒してみろ 俺を！
And come back up after me!
Take me on again!
くっ… バカが
You idiot.
言われずとも そうするさ
You don't even have to tell me that.
当然だ！
Of course I will!
待ってろ！
Wait for me!
叩き潰す！
Next time, I will destroy you!
次は！
こうしてカイジ 対 一条
そのパチンコ勝負は終わった
And thus, the pachinko duel between Kaiji and Ichijou concluded.
地下カジノの主 ｢沼｣は
しぶとく執拗に抗い続けたが
The Bog, the master of the underground casino,
has put up a long and determined resistance.
最後の最後に力尽き 放出した
But finally, its strength sapped, it paid out.
そのはらわたの全てを！
Paid out everything in its guts!
そして換金！
And then, the exchange!
見たことも
想像したこともない大金
A fortune the likes of which Kaiji had never seen nor even imagined!
７億2910万！
729,100,000 yen!
まず 皆に祝儀
First, they celebrate!
そして 返済
Then, the repayment!
何はともあれ帝愛の借金
924万を返済する
Before anything else, Kaiji repays his debt of 9,240,000 yen!
ほら 持ってけ 吸血野郎！
There! Take it, you bloodsuckers!
クソ野郎！あんな紙切れで
人を奴隷扱いしやがって
You shitheads try to bleed men, drop by drop, until they become your slaves!
ざまあみろ　文句あるまい！
This is what you get! How d'you like that!?
俺は自由だ！
I'm free!
借金ゼロ！金持ち！
日本一の金持ち！
I don't owe a cent!
In fact, I'm rich!  The richest man in Japan!
わしも！
Me too!
え？
俺も！
And me too!
３人 金持ち！億万長者！
All three of us are rich!
Millionaires!
そして分配！
Now, to split the money!
この時点で残金７億1786万
At this moment, there's 717,860,000 yen left!
ここからカイジが使った金を
遠藤と坂崎に分配
First, Endoh and Sakazaki take the same amount of money Kaiji's already spent!
３人 同一条件とする
The three even up!
そして遠藤から借りた工作費
Next, Endoh's construction budget, stack, and interest are paid!
当日の軍資金と
利子１億1326万が遠藤へ
Endoh takes 113,260,000 yen!
さらに途中の追加軍資金が
Then, Kaiji's extra loans are paid back to Endoh and Sakazaki!
遠藤と坂崎にそれぞれ返され
残ったのは
568,120,000 remain!
５億6812万！これが純益
This is the net profit!
これを３等分
１人頭 １億8937万！
Each of them gets 189,370,000 yen!
イヤッホー！
割り切れない１万は
カイジがもらい 分配終了！
Kaiji takes the remaining bill, and the money is split!
カンパーイ！
Cheers!
さあさあ！こりゃ俺のおごりだ
おごり？
Look at it all!
We're rich!
遠慮は無用！
さあ飲もう！あとは飲もうぜ！
Let's drink!
しかしええのう 遠藤はんは
あ？
Man, you're lucky, Endoh.
だって１人だけ夢の３億超え
You're walking out of here with more than 300 mil.
ほんまに羨ましい
I'm really jealous.
ああ… うん…
わしなんか
I put up 50 million to begin with, so I'm only really getting about 150 out of it.
この勝負の前に5000万
いかれてもうてるから
実質の儲けは１億5000万ほどや
わしが一番 実入りが少ないんや
I kinda get the short end of the stick...
いや ペケは俺さ
No. That's me.
話してなかったっけ
カ… カイジくん…
Didn't I tell you?
Kaiji?
俺には救わなきゃならねえ仲間が
５人いるんだ
I have five friends I need to save.
地の底でともに
艱難辛苦を超えてきた仲間が
Friends I suffered with underground.
今回 俺がシャバで
こんなバクチが打てたのも
It's thanks to them that I even made it out here to gamble.
みんなの力なんだ
みんなの汗と涙と忍耐と
Their sweat, their tears, their endurance... That's how I'm here today.
そういうものの結晶として
奇跡的に今 俺はここにいる
…ってわけだから その５人の救済
So I need to get them out and pay them back.
借金返済だけは しなきゃならない
その費用が約5000万
It's gonna be about 50 mil.
さらに残った１億4000万も
その５人と俺で割る
And I'm splitting the 140 left with them.
はあ？
割る？
You're splitting it!?
連中は 言うなら俺の外ウマに
乗ったんだから
They bet on me.
当然 利益は６人で
割らなきゃいけない
So I need to split what I won with them.
とすると １人頭およそ2300万
That leaves each of us with 23 million or so.
えっ？ちょ… ちょっと待てよ
カイジくん
Wait, Kaiji! You don't have to go that far!
そこまですることは なかろう
地下の仲間か何か知らんが
６等分は やりすぎ
I don't know how close you guys got down there, but a six-way split is overkill!
地下から救い出せば それで十分
Just getting them out is enough!
それ以上の報酬は せんでいい
They don't need any more!
まあまあ　あの金をどう使おうと
カイジの勝手だ
Eh, it's up to Kaiji how he spends his money.
そ… そりゃそうやが…
認めるしかねえだろ
I guess....
Just deal with it, okay?
要するに立派ってこった
It's pretty badass, to be honest.
今時 珍しい友情厚き男ってわけだ
Here's a man who really knows the value of friendship.
よせよ
うーん 分からん
Aww, c'mon.
I just don't get it!
分からん！何でそうなるんか
Why do you have to do that?
だから外ウマってのはな
そういうもんなんだよ
I told you, they bet on me!
バカ！さっきの一条の件といい
That idiot.
He proved just how naïve he is with Ichijou.
大甘！
直ってねえ
He's never gonna change.
こいつの妙な善人ぶり
He's never gonna get over trying to be the nice guy.
いい加減にせえよ
しょうがねえだろ
約束しちまったもんは！
すくわれて当然だな
こんなんじゃ足を
He's still an easy mark.
進歩ゼロ！
He hasn't learned a thing.
いずれ食い殺される
そんな考えじゃ！
Sooner or later, someone'll hang him out to dry.
救えねえ
He's never gonna change.
ええ人や！わしが間違っとった！
You're such a great guy!
I was wrong about you!
カイジくん
え？
Kaiji! You can have my... My...
わしの大事な…
金？
Money?
金より大事な…
はあ？
Something more important than money!
美心を！
Mikoko!
ええっ？
持ってけ 泥棒！
Take her, you bandit!
え… 遠慮しときます
I just can't.
カーッ 何て慎み深い！
You don't have to hold back!
いやいや 慎みじゃなくて…
Believe me, I'm not!
気に入った！
ますます気に入った！
You've fallen for her! I know you have!
お… おっちゃん
Pops?
あーあ　へっ 大して
飲んでねえのに だらしがねえ
What a lightweight.
ねえ 遠藤さ…
Right, En... doh?
あ… あれ？
Huh?
Whaaa?
無味無臭の睡眠薬
Tasteless, scentless sleeping pills.
水に入れても気づかない代物だ
You wouldn't even notice them in water.
まっ ４～５時間 眠っててくれ
Why don't you take a little nap?
そして４時間後
Four hours pass.
あ… なっ 何だ？
Huh?
寝ちまったのか？
Did I fall asleep?
あれ？いない
Huh, where'd he go?
あれ？遠藤さん？
Hey? Endoh?
おっちゃん　おっちゃん 起きろ
Pops! Get up!
消えたぞ　遠藤さんが
Endoh's gone!
トイレやないのか？
You sure?
確かめたが いない
えっ？
I just checked.
ああ？ああ！
ハァー 大丈夫や
Don't worry. He probably just went to pay his loans off.
多分 借金返しに行ったんやろ
あ… なっ ない！
It's gone!
No, it's not all here!
ていうか 少ない！俺の金
My money! It's gone, gone!
えっ？
ない　ない
To Kaiji
喜びの宴に水を差すのも
何だと思い
Sorry to rain on your parade, but I had to take the money and run.
こんな形で切り出すしかなかった
実は最後に俺が
トイレで貸し付けた1000万
The ten million you borrowed from me in the bathroom...
その金利をもらっていなかった
I forgot to charge you the interest.
同封してあるあの時の借用書を
よーく見てほしい
Take a close look at the contract you signed.
おお！
うわ！ひどっ…
That's terrible!
明記してあるだろう
It should be as clear as day.
｢10分３割複利｣と
Compound interest, 30% per ten minutes.
俺が あの1000万を渡したのが
午後12時15分
I lent you that 10 million at 12:15.
大当たりが決まり
返済可能となったのが
You hit the jackpot and could pay it back at 1:47.
午後１時47分
その間 92分
That's 92 minutes.
つまり 1000万を３割複利で
10回 回した計算になり
So the 30% interest compounded ten times.
その金利は…
That makes the interest 127,850,000 yen.
１億2785万になる
う… ぐうっ…
カイジくん
Kaiji...
これは お前に個人的に
貸し付けた借金だから
You borrowed it yourself, so I took it out of your share.
お前の取り分から
受け取っていくぞ　悪く思うなよ
Fair's fair, right?
これは俺の当然の権利なのだ
I had the right to it.
ふざけ… ふざけんなよ 遠藤！
Give me a fucking break, Endoh!
ふざけ… ふざけやがって　遠藤！
You cocksucker! Endoh, you cocksucker!
結局 １億8938万から
127,850,000 yen is taken from Kaiji's 189,380,000, reducing him to 61,530,000!
１億2785万を取られ
残ったのは6153万！
じゃあ 名残惜しいが
俺はこれで失礼する
Anyway, it's a shame we have to part, but I'll be leaving now.
体に気をつけて暮らせよ
Take care, Kaiji, my dear friend.
親愛なるカイジへ
Why me!? Why does this always happen to me!?
な… 何でこんな目に…
俺が… 俺だけが…
カ… カイジくん…
Kaiji...
あ！そうそう
Oh, right!
わしも そろそろ行かんと
I need to get going.
返さないかんからな 例の金庫の金
Need to put that money back in the safe and all. See you!
し… 失礼するで
くわばらくわばら　｢やっぱり
もう少しよこせ！｣とか何とか
Knock on wood, that juju doesn't rub off.
I need to get away from him before it starts happening to me too.
言いかねん状況
ここは早々に退散や
I'm outta here.
それでも寝た
Still, he sleeps!
沼との死闘に疲れ
その数日前からの不眠
Exhausted from his battle with the Bog, and his sleepless nights!
それらが重なり カイジは寝た
The weight of these pressures forces Kaiji to sleep!
あ！ええ？
フン 失礼していいかな
May we come in?
何だよ お前ら
もう俺に用はねえはずだろ
What do you want!? I paid you back!
確かにそのとおりだ
Yes. But there was a mistake.
だが 不覚にも失念した
え？
出るはずのない沼の大当たり
などという異常事態に面食らい
We were so surprised that you did the impossible and made the Bog cough up
that we forgot one thing.
動転　うっかり忘れちまった
最後の仕事を
One last task.
ったく 忘れんなよ バカ！
こんな大事なことを
Jeez. How the hell did you forget some thing like this!?
ハハハ お前
またハメられたんだってな
I heard you got fucked over again.
あ？
ひでえ話だ
100 mil in interest for 92 minutes? Seriously?
92分の金利が１億なんぼなんて
さっき遠藤が帝愛に金を
返しに来て話してたよ 楽そうにな
Endoh wouldn't shut up about it when he came to pay us back.
あの野郎！
That son of a bitch.
よし 終了だ
There you go. It's over.
さて どうする？
あ？
What are you gonna do now?
お前 まだ地下の仲間とやらを
救うとか何とか
Didn't you say you were gonna save your friends from the underground?
のたまってんだってな？
はっ…
今一度 確認したい
I want to make one thing clear.
何しろ状況が変わったからな
I don't know what happened, but that 190 mil or so of yours is cut down to about sixty.
１億9000万近くあった金が
今 6000万強
これで５人を救ったら
Bust the five of them out, and you've got 10 mil.
残りは約1000万
さらにそれを６等分なんてしたら
Split what's left, and you're looking at 1.7 each.
１人頭170万ほど
雀の涙もいいとこ
That ain't shit, to be honest.
ゴミみてえな金だ
You may as well be picking for cans in the trash.
しかし 今そのクソみてえな約束を
反故にしちまえば
But blow them off and you keep it all.
全取り！
6000万強という大金が
全てお前のものだ
60 mil, all for you.
悪魔のささやきってやつか
What kind of devil's temptation is that supposed to be?
いや いやいや　普通普通
Oh, it's normal. Perfectly normal. Just normal human temptation.
ごく普通　普通の人間のささやき
Quit showing off, man. Go for what you really want.
いいから持ってけ！5000万
Take the 50 mil.
え？お… おいおい 本気か？
Seriously? Shouldn't you worry about yourself?
まずは自分の利益の確保が先だろ
本気も何も 当たり前だろ！
Of course I'm serious.
裏切れるかよ 仲間を
I can't betray my friends.
救い出す！必ず！
I will save them.
噂どおり 変な男だ
You really are a weirdo.
いいだろう　手配しよう
Oh well, your call.
もう１つ それとは別に頼みがある
There's one other thing I'd like to ask.
うっ… 来た！
There they are!
ああ… いる！
They're all there!
みんな！間違いない 連中だ！
It's them! My friends! The 45s!
しかも仲間！４５組だ！
やった！やったやった！
All right! We did it!
あと もう１人
Wait, there's one more!
本気か それ？
ああ
Are you sure?
Yeah.
し… しかし 何でまた
そんな関係ない男を？
Why? He doesn't even have anything to do with you.
確かに奴とは地下で
一度 顔を合わせただけ
Yeah, I only met him once down there.
正直 いい印象ではなかった
It wasn't a very pleasant encounter either.
話にならねえ甘ったれで
He's a total grifter.
でも 預かっちまったんだ
But I owe his father one from way back.
その男の父親から 昔
ちょうど その男が救われる金
1000万を
He gave me enough money to save him. Ten million.
もし石田のおっさんが生きてたら
If Ishida was still alive, he'd save his son.
あんな野郎でも
救ったに違いないんだ
救える金を手にしたなら
きっと救っていた
So if I have the money, I'm going to.
なら 救わなきゃよ 俺が！
I have to!
いろいろあったが 何はともあれ
Even with everything that's happened, I've got ten million left.
今 1000万 金が残ったんだから
救わなきゃ
I have to save him.
だが ６分の１なんだ
あ？
But only a sixth of it is really mine.
この残金1000万の俺の取り分は
６分の１
Only a sixth of this ten million belongs to me.
この金は４５組みんなのもの
This money belongs to all of us 45s.
だから俺の独断で決定はできない
So I can't decide this on my own.
そこでだ　聞いてみてくれ 奴らに
I need you to ask them for me.
もし誰か１人でも
If any one of them is too hardhearted to give up his 1.7 million, then so be it.
｢そんなお人よしはできない｣
｢それより当座の資金170万が大事｣
そう言う者がいたらしょうがない
当然の意見だしな
I can understand why.
諦めよう この話は
If so, I'll give up.
でももし 俺の思いを
受け入れてくれて
But if!
If they understand me! If they say they'll save him!
救う… 救おうと言ってくれたら
出してやってくれ
Get him out! Save Ishida!
あの石田を
あの男は？
There he is!
石田！ううっ…
Ishida!
すまねえ… みんな
I'm so sorry, everyone!
ていうかお前ら いい奴じゃんか
You're all such awesome guys!
カイジさんは？
カイジさんはどこだよ？
Huh, what about Kaiji?
Where's Kaiji?
さあ　散れ！散れ 散れ！
Scram, you hear?
でもカイジさんが…
いいから散れ！
What about Kaiji?
Move it!
いつまでたまってる　散れ！
How long are you gonna stand there?
Clear out! Now!
さあ 散れ 散れ！
分からん男だな
I don't get you.
どうした？
どうして会いに行かない？
What's wrong?
Why didn't you go see them? They were waiting for you.
みんな会いたがってたぞ
でも …ねがないから
は？
But I'm flat out.
あ… あの 金がないから…
I'm broke.
え？バカな
What?
Really? Penniless?
ねえってこと ねえだろ
石田の救出金が
1000万ちょいだったから
Even after Ishida, there should have been about 600 thou left. A hundred each.
60万ほど残って
その６分の１の10万
昨日 お前に渡しただろ
I gave it to you myself yesterday. Where'd it all go?
なんでねえんだよ その金が？
パチンコで…
はっ？パチンコ？
Pachinko...
Pachinko?
まさか すっちまったのか 10万？
You blew a hundred thou on pachinko in a single day?
１日で おい？
バカ！残しとけよ
Are you an idiot? You knew you were meeting them today, you should've saved some!
分かってるだろ 今日会うことは
熱くなって 気がついたら…
I got caught up in the game and lost track...
聞きたかねえ そんなクズの常套句
Wow, you really are trash.
まーったく
Jeez, why can't you go meet them even if you're broke?
それに 金がなくったって
会うことぐらい できるだろ
そんな！会ったら絶対
飲み食いになるじゃないっすか
I can't! I know they'd want to go out for dinner and drinks!
そん時 金がないから
おごってくれなんて とても…
I can't just sponge off of them...
あ？何言ってんだ お前？
What's your problem?
いや 何て言うか 連中から見たら
俺 ヒーローだから…
They must think I'm some kind of hero!
かーっ 何だその見栄 まったく
Jeez, do you really have to think of it like that?
謙虚なんだか傲慢なんだか
分からん男だ
I don't even know if you're too humble or too proud!
チェッ
ほれ
え？
Here.
３万ある　これで奴らと
合流してこい
Thirty thou.
Go hang out with them.
え？
やる
Do it.
やる？やるって…
Do it? You mean?
タダだ
タダ？帝愛が？
Just go ahead.
Go ahead?  You mean Teiai—
帝愛じゃねえ　俺だ
It ain't from Teiai! It's from me!
俺がタダでやるって言ってんだ
I'm telling you, just take it!
だから行け　合流してこい
Go and hang out with them, you shitty excuse for a hero!
クソヒーロー
おじさん…
行け
Man...
Go!
やさしいおじさん…
さっさと消えろ
You're such a nice guy!
Just get out of here.
ありがとうございます！
忘れません　このご恩は 一生！
Thanks! I'll never forget this!
クッ…
似合わないことしますね
That wasn't like you at all.
内緒だぞ　会長には
Don't tell the Chairman.
Okay.
カ… カイジさん！
Kaiji!
The future is in our hands!
We don't need your rules
We don't need your morals
We don't need your schools
We'll only grasp onto the truth
We weren't born to cry
We weren't born to lose
We weren't born for that
Proverbs of Kaiji Returns!
Gambling is... Dirtier than that. Fool.
It feels like endless ejaculation!
In a way, this is his utopia!
Don't just wait for a miracle.
Even a fool or scum has a chance to win!
The Proverbs of Kaiji: A collection of miraculous proverbs!
We're giving away Nobuyuki Fukumoto's famous sayings on how to turn your life around!
For more info, visit our mobile site!
The future is in our hands!